Guide to the Associate Dean of Students records, 1931-1978.
Associate Dean of Students records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Associate Dean of Students records, 1931-1978.
37-1-1790
Cornell University. Associate Dean of Students.
8.9 cubic ft.
Correspondence, publications, reports
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Files of Associate Dean of Students Ruth W. Darling including records of the Women's Judiciary Board and the Women's Self Government Association, Women's Student Government Association.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Files of Associate Dean of Students Ruth W. Darling include records of the Women's Judiciary Board, the Women's Self Government Association, Women's Student Government Association, staff meetings, scholarships and funds, student housing, fraternities, and other topics; includes memoranda, reports, senate actions, and registration forms for major campus events.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Darling, Ruth W.; Cornell University -- Administration.; Cornell University. Women's Judiciary Board.; Cornell University. Women's Self Government Association.; Cornell University. Women's Student Goverment Association.; Cornell University. Women's Self Government Association.; Cornell University. Women's Student Government Association.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Boxes 5 and 11 are restricted to permission of office of origin.
CONTAINER LIST
- Annual Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Annual Reports, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Annual Reports, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Annual Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Annual Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Freshmen Men's Residence Dining Requirements, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Risley Library Fund, 1948-1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Six Year Ph.D. Program, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- House Committee Cases, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Von Cramm Scholarship Residence Hall, 1955-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Sage Graduate Center, 1953-1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Sage Graduate Center, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Women's Student Government Association (W.S.G.A.), 1949-1957 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- W.S.G.A. Advising Committee, 1949-1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- W.S.G.A. Social Committee, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- W.S.G.A. Correspondence, Reports, 1959-1966 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Regulations on use of Alcoholic Beverages in Dormitories, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Conference on Student Personnel Programs, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Cayuga Lodge, Inc. (630 Stewart Avenue), 1949-1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Staff Meetings, 1945-1958 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Helen Magill White's house, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Warning Notices re: Cayuga Lake, 1947-1952 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- VIA Incorporated, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Letters and Memos, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- COED Dormitories, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Letters and Memos, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Letters and Memos, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Cornell Women's Club, 1960-1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Margaret Crouch Nottingham Fund, 1956-1963 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Margaret Crouch Nottingham Fund, 1942-1950 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Margaret Crouch Nottingham Fund, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Georgia Laura White Fund - General Historical Information, 1950-1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Georgia Laura White Fund (Disbursements), 1954-1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Laura Osborn Memorial Scholarship, 1942-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Dean of Women's Grant Fund, 1944-1964 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Space Problems of Housing and Dining, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Ithaca Women's Club - Scholarship Grants, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Meyer's Committee on Student Housing, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Meyer's Committee on Student Housing, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Approved Housing Legislation, 1964-1969 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Dormitory Construction and Operation, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Dormitory Construction and Operation, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- History of Cornell Housing, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Committee on Student Aid, 1956-1961 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Tri-Delt Scholarship Committee, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Student Housing at Cornell, 1965-67 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Report on Cornell Dormitory Construction, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Human Rights Committee, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Human Rights Committee, 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Student Housing Demands, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Ithace Housing Market, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- First Issue, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Political articles by Ithaca-Cornell Students for a Democratic Society (SDS), 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Clippings and Pamphlets on Student Housing Needs, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Human Rights Committee, 1961-1965 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Memos to Milton Shaw From Katherine Morus, 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Cornell Dames Fund, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Florence Dearstyne Fund, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Apartment Construction, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Mary Donlon Hall, 1954-1960 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Mary Donlon Hall, 1961-1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Proposed Apartment Construction, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Proposed Apartment Construction, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Proposed Apartment Construction, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Housing Considerations, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Dormitory Open House Regulations, 1960-1965 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Dormitory Open House Regulations, 1966-1969 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Letters and Memos concerning Curfew, 1963-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Residence Requirements, 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Recondo Group Rental of DeWitt Place Property, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Freshman Humanities Courses, 1966-1969 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Discrimination Problems in Social Organizations, 1960-1965 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Commission on Discrimination Legislation, 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Commission on Discrimination Legislation, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Fraternities on Campus, 1960-1967 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Cornell United Religious Work, 1966-1973 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Five Day Rule, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Fall Weekends, 1959-1967 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Housing Statistics, 1960-1965 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Housing Statistics, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Housing Statistics, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Housing Statistics, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Housing Statistics, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Housing Statistics, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Reports on Fraternities, 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Exemption Committee, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Faculty Committee on Student Conduct, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Crisis on the Cornell Campus, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Crisis on the Cornell Campus, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- National Strike Call Against War in Indochina, Political Repression and ROTC, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Reports to the Trustees Commission on Residential Environment, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Community Relations Council, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Housing Needs Projections, 1971-1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Disposition of 640 Stewart Avenue, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Marriage Lecture Series, 1950-1961 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- W.S.G.A. Disposition of Funds, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- W.S.G.A. Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Ithaca Area Girls Entering Cornell, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- W.S.G.A. Reports, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Dornitory Newsletters, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- W.S.G.A. Minutes, Clippings and Handbooks, 1961-1969 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Housing Committee on Various Dormitory Situations, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Ruth Darling Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Ruth Darling Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Ruth Darling Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Ruth Darling Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Residential Council, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Ruth Darling Correspondence, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Ruth Darling Correspondence, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Contract Dining Plans, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Men's Dormitory Programs and Guidelines, 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Renovations of University Halls and Baker Dormitories, 1965-1969 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Ruth Darling Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Ruth Darling Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Ruth Darling Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Research Project of D'Ann Lee Roch, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Men's Dormitories; Memos on Student Housing, 1959-1962 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Women's Dormitory Improvements, 1964-1968 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Women's Dormitory Improvements, 1960-1968 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Women's Dormitory Improvements, 1955-1963 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Housing Surveys for Seniors, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Non-Dormitory Students, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Memos on Some Aspects of Administration in Cornell University, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- W.S.G.A. Publications: Rules, Constitutions, 1919-1967 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1951-1957 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Publications: Co-ed's Creed, So You're a Cornell Co-ed, 1951-1968 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- W.S.G.A. Summer Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- W.S.G.A. Summer Correspondence, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Permission for Selling Items on Campus, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Janet Reno Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Dormitory Matters, 1948-1961 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- W.S.G.A. Election Proceedures, 1952-1956 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- W.S.G.A. Policy Decisions, 1955-1967 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Judiciary Case of Elinor Steinmann, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Judicial Matters, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Report on Student Affairs, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- W.S.G.A. Financial Proceedings, 1953-1969 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- W.S.G.A. Officers, 1956-1963 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Dormitory V.P.'s, 1953-1960 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Dormitory V.P.'s, 1960-1962 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- W.S.G.A. Vice President's Reports, 1940-1955 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- W.S.G.A. Special Permissions Board Report, 1952-1960 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Secretary Reports, 1953-1961 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- W.S.G.A. Program Coordinator, 1956-1964 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- W.S.G.A. President's Reports, 1959-1969 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Dormitory President's Reports, 1958-1963 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- W.S.G.A. VP Selection, Election and Training, 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Dormitory President's Manual, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Residential Committee Minutes, 1956-1960 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Residential Committee Minutes, 1961-1963 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Residential Committee Minutes, 1953-1955 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Residential Committee Minutes, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Residential Council, 1966-1969 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- W.S.G.A. Executive Committee, 1953-1958 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- W.S.G.A. Executive Committee, 1959-1970 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Executive Board of Student Government, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- W.S.G.A. Executive Board, 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- W.S.G.A. House of Representatives Minutes, 1956-1958 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- W.S.G.A. Assembly Minutes, 1960-1969 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Minutes of University Faculty Committee on Student Affairs, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Ithaca Freshman Girls Living in Dormitories and Elsewhere, 1959-1962 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Surveys on Dormitory Living, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- W.S.G.A. Proposal for Integrated Dorms, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- W.S.G.A. Applications and Interviews, 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- W.S.G.A. Executive Board, 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Joseph Bugliari's Committee to Review the Judicial System, 1967-1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Joseph Bugliari's Committee to Review the Judicial System, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Cornell University Residence Plan (CURP), 1966-1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Ujamaa Residential College, 1972-1976 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Ujamaa Residential College, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Staff Retreats, 1972-1979 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Shortages and Accommodations of Student Housing, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Shortages and Accommodations of Student Housing, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- President's Committee to Review the Judicial System, 1972-1978 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- President's Committee to Review the Judicial System, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- "The Trojan Horse" Campus Magazine, 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Secretary of State Dean Rusk's Campus Visit, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Viet Nam Ad Hoc Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Finance Commission on Student Government, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Cornell Student Government, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- W.S.G.A. Scholarships, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Cornell University Student Code, 1960-1962 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Cornell University Student Code, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Disciplinary Action at Cornell University, 1953-1960 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Freshman Residence Judiciary Board, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Student Motivation Sub-Committee, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Joint Committee on Faculty-Student Relations, 1958-1963 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Faculty Committee on Student Conduct, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Faculty Committee on Student Conduct, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Faculty Committee on Student Conduct, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Faculty Committee on Student conduct, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Codes and Judiciary Committee, 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Codes and Judiciary Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Reports on Student Housing, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Campus Housing, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Reports on Student Housing, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Reports on Student Housing, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Reports on Student Housing, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Reports on Student Housing, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Project for Student Housing on the Country Club Site, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Housing Committee Reports, 1969-1973 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Housing for Future Needs, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Housing for Future Needs, 1972-1974 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Senate Housing Subcommittee, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Senate Housing Subcommittee, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Drug Education, 1967-1970 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Drug Education, 1967-1971 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Drug Education, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Drug Education, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Drug Education, 1974-1979 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Student Organizations, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Student Activities, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Drug Issue on Campus, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Student Life at Cornell, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Ithaca Model Housing Code, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Campus Planning Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Student Organizations and Activities, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Student Organizations and Activities, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Student Organizations and Activities, 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Student Organizations and Activities, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Student Organizations and Activities, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Student Organizations and Activities, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Student Organizations and Activities, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Student Organizations and Activities, Use of University Property and Commercial Endeavors, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Student Organizations and Activities, Use of University Property and Commercial Endeavors, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Student Organizations and Activities, Use of University Property and Commercial Endeavors, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Student Organizations and Activities, Use of University Property and Commercial Endeavors, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Student Organizations and Activities, Use of University Property and Commercial Endeavors, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Student Organizations and Activities, Use of University Property and Commercial Endeavors, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Registration of Major Events and Speakers, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Registration of Major Events and Speakers, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Registration of Major Events and Speakers, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Registration of Major Events and Speakers, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Registration of Major Events and Room Reservation Forms, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Registration of Major Events and Room Reservation Forms, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Registration of Major Events and Room Reservation Forms, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Registration of Major Events and Room Reservation Forms, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Registration of Major Events and Room Reservation Forms, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Registration of Major Events and Speaker Reservation Forms, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Registration of Major Events and Room Reservation Forms, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Registration of Major Events and Room Reservation Forms, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Registration of Major Events and Room Reservation Forms, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Registration of Major Events and Room Reservation Forms, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Confidential Report on Student Discipline, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Executive Council Meeting Minutes, 1931-1937 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Study Dealing with Problems of Residence Hall Personnel, 1939-1941 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Intercollegiate Association of Women Students Convention Notebook, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Cornell Student Government Booklets, 1961-1963 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Letter to Parents Concerning Overnight Absences, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Reflections on Current State of the University, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- W.S.G.A. Report on Curfews for Senior Women, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Speeches from American Personnel and Guidance Association, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Speeches from National Association of Women Deans and Counselors, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Proceedures for Leaving and Returning to Living Units for Senior Women, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- W.S.G.A. Residential Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Lits of Suggested Improvements in Dormitories, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- W.S.G.A. V.P. Training for Dormitories, 1963-1965 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- W.S.G.A. V.P. for Dormitories, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Dormitory Presidents Reports, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- W.S.G.A. Officers and Candidates, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- W.S.G.A. Officers, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Special Permissions Board, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- W.S.G.A. Program Coordinator, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Special Permissions and Standardized Penalties, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Dormitory Presidents, Resident Advisors, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- W.S.G.A. Officers, 1964-1966 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- W.S.G.A. Constitution and Minutes, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- W.S.G.A. Program Council, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Women's Judiciary Board Cases, 1958-1959 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Women's Judiciary Board Cases, 1960-1961 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Women's Judiciary Board Cases, 1961-1962 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Women's Judiciary Board Cases, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Women's Judiciary Board Cases, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Women's Judiciary Board Cases, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Residential Club Fire, 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 7)